本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：Silmar     Joanna     灰兔灰兔     泡泡龙
翻译：meredith49     叶子飘零     时间轴：Angelica
■
精校：胔宁  后期：冰河  特效：WiLL   校对&监制：蛐蛐
绝
命
毒
师
第三季
第一集
本台中断预播节目
We interrupt our scheduled programming
插播一则重大新闻
to bring you breaking news.
下午好
Good afternoon.
刚刚的几分钟里
In the last several minutes,
KOB电视台收到了数十个
KOB has received dozens of reports
关于阿尔布开克东部一起
of what appears to be a crashed aircraft--
疑似两架航班相撞事故的电话
possibly two aircraft on Albuquerque's east side.
目前事故的细节尚不清楚
As of yet, details are scarce,
但据报告者描述  他们目睹了上空的爆炸
But callers describe witnessing an explosion overhead,
及其坠落的残骸  空中仍可见尘埃弥漫
followed by falling debris. Visible now toward...
国家运输安全委员会
...crash investigators
的事故调查人员
with the National Transportation Safety Board
将于今晚到达事故现场
are expected on-site as early as this evening.
但官员们也提醒
But officials warn that,
事故残骸覆盖面积如此之广
with a debris field of this magnitude,
调查和残骸清理工作可能会持续较长时间
the investigation and the clean-up may well stretch--
联邦航空管理局发言人称
...are now saying that the Boeing 737
该架波音737当时正在指挥塔调度下
was being re-routed or vectored through the airspace,
更改航线
which is standard procedure,
其间一切操作均符合规程
according to a spokesman for the FAA.
8座的空中之王350
The eight-seat King Air 350
是从犹他州的圣乔治城起飞
was a charter flight operating out of Saint George, Utah,
飞往德克萨斯州的阿马里洛
bound for Amarillo, Texas.
听上去像下冰雹
It sounded like hail.
石头一样的大冰雹
Like heavy hailstones.
简直就是...
It was just, um...
梆梆梆地砸落到整个街区
bump-bump-bump all over the neighborhood.
调查显示最终的遇难人数是167人
...indicating that the final death toll now stands at 167.
167人遇难
..67 muertos--
167人
...167...
此次空中相撞事件让人们不禁质疑
This mid-air collision has left many wondering
在如此严谨的安防措施下
how such an accident could take place
为何还会发生这样恶劣的事故
in a system with so many safeguards.
甚至有人指控造成5号航班
Allegations continue that the collision
撞机的原因
which brought down Flight 5
是错误的空中指挥
was caused by improper air traffic control.
这一惊人消息已被俄克拉荷马城的
The bombshell confirmation out of Oklahoma City today,
联邦航空管理局证明属实
as the FAA confirmed, it was, indeed,
事故归因为一名空中交通管制员的失误
a lone air traffic controller's fateful mistake...
这名男子的姓名是唐纳德·马戈利斯
...que el nombre del hombre es Donald Margolis.
是唐纳德·马戈利斯
...is Donald Margolis,
联邦航空管理局19年的老员工
a 19-year veteran of the FAA's
服务于阿尔布开克空中航线交通控制中心
Air Route Traffic Control Center in Albuquerque.
马戈利斯休假五周后
...Margolis recently returned to work
第一天开始工作
after a five-week absence,
休假原因  据称是亲人离世
which was due to, quote, a personal loss.
现已查明
While it's now known
马戈利斯的女儿一个月前
that Margolis had recently lost a daughter...
因吸毒过量死亡
...to a drug overdose a month before.
他的女儿名叫珍妮·马戈利斯  26岁
His troubled daughter Jane Margolis, aged 26,
有长期吸毒史
apparently had a long history of substance abuse.
马戈利斯家的朋友们认为  独生女儿的死
And friends of the family say the death of his only child
对他打击巨大
hit Margolis particularly hard.
由于两起事件相隔仅一个月
Coming as it did little more than a month before,
有人质疑他返岗工作的时间是否恰当
many are questioning the timing of his return to work,
并指问让这位悲恸的父亲
and are wondering how much blame truly lies
返岗工作的人该负何种责任
with those who let this grieving father--
不  不
No. No, no.
我通常会先说  你来到这里我很遗憾
I usually open with "So sorry you're here."
你想从哪里谈起
Where would you like to begin?
我只想快一点结束
I really just need this quick and easy, you know?
越快越好
As quick as something like this can be.
好的
Okay.
是双方的决定吗
Is that mutual?
你丈夫同意了吗
Does your husband go along with that?
他知情吗
Does he know?
我是说
Well, I mean,
他当然知道我们已经分开了  所以
he certainly knows we're separated, so--
他搬出去了吗
Has he moved out?
这事我们正在办
We're in the process of moving him out.
嗯  希望是  今天
Yeah. Today, hopefully.
现在  我的
And in the meantime, my--
儿子和女儿
my son and my daughter
跟我一起住在我妹妹家
and I are staying with my sister.
这么说是你搬出去了
So you've moved out?
是的  只是暂时的
Well, yes, just temporarily,
为了方便他收拾东西
only so he could get his things.
本该是上周搬的
That was supposed to happen last week,
但是发生了撞机  然后
but then came the crash, and--
哦  天哪
Oh, God.
你家不会是
You weren't one of the-- Right--
是的  就在航线正下方
Yeah. Right beneath the flight path.
然后
And, um...
我家的院子
uh, we had debris land in our yard
-和整个街区满是残骸  -太可怕了
- and all of our neighborhood, so-  - Mmm. Terrible.
是啊  甚至
Yeah. Apparently, even, um...
还有  尸体碎片
you know, parts of bodies,
所以我当然不能...
and so I certainly couldn't bring myself to--
-太可怕了  -是啊
- So awful. - I know.
我当时不能搬回去  但现在可以了
Anyway, I was certainly not ready to move back, but it's time.
我想我妹妹和妹夫一定被我们烦死了
I'm sure we're driving my sister and her husband up a wall.
你一定要回到自己家中居住
Well, you definitely want to maintain residency in your actual home.
在争取抚养权方面  才能占据主动
It just puts you in a better position in regards to custody.
你说你们有两个孩子
Two children, you said?
对  这是小女儿霍莉
Yes. Holly here,
还有个儿子在上高中
and then I have a son in high school--
名叫小沃尔特
Walter Junior.
他们得跟着我过
They need to stay with me.
了解
Okay.
结婚多久了
How long have you been married?
16年
Sixteen years.
住的不是公寓楼  是幢房子是吧
And it's not an apartment. It's a house that you live in?
贷款付清了吗
Do you own outright?
-仍在按揭吗  -对
- Do you have a mortgage? - Yes.
当然是按揭的  还有...
There's definitely a mortgage. We have, um...
大概15年贷款未付
maybe 15 years on it.
其他债务或资产呢
What about other debts or assets?
你对你们夫妻双方的财务状况
Do you feel you have a good understanding
是否有充分的了解
of you and your husband's financial situation?
你丈夫有工作吗
Is your husband employed?
我先跟你说清楚
You know what? Here's the thing.
我真的没想要
I-- I'm really not looking
找什么漏洞或是想...
for any, sort of, uh, loopholes or--
钻什么空子之类的
I don't know-- just-- No.
不是钻空子
No loopholes.
我只想让我的每位客户
I just intend that every one of my clients
对自己婚内的资产及负债状况
get a full and honest accounting
都能够有全面如实的了解
of what it is they owe and what it is they own.
为此  希望能够知无不言
To that end, I say let's leave no stone unturned.
你无法想象
You'd be amazed
有多少夫妻双方隐瞒财产的案例
what I've seen partners hide from one another.
沃尔特
Walt?
沃尔特  在家吗
Hey, Walt?
兄弟  你在这啊
Hey. Hey, buddy, there you are.
是这样的
Listen, I, uh-- You know, well--
差不多该出发了
It's, uh...time.
911以来最糟的一周  绝无仅有
The shittiest week since 9/11, okay? Bar none.
真的  不容置疑  绝对是的
Yeah, this is it. Hands down, we're living it.
我跟主管当局有些人谈过
I mean, I speak with some authority
在过去的数月里
because we definitely had some shitty weeks
有好几周都很糟很乱
in the past few months, you know?
但这周发生的事情  实在是...
But this here, I mean, call, you know--
简直能上吉尼斯世界记录
call freakin' the Guinness Book of World Records--
我是不是话太多了
Call freakin'-- Am I talking too much?
是吗  肯定是的吧  我就知道
Am I? I am, right? I am. I know. Look, look.
但你们俩现在这情况...
But this situation between you and, uh-- uh--
我不是打听八卦啊
I'm not asking, by the way.
这本就不关我的事
Okay? It's none of my business.
我也不想介入你们俩这事
I do not want to get in the middle of you two.
我的意思是...听一下总成吧
I'm just saying-- Listen, listen-- Okay?
你就当这是战略性转移吧 懂我意思
You beat a little tactical retreat. Yeah?
然后再回家来
And regroup.
然后...就没事了
And then-- bong.
小别一下  回来就好了...
You know, absence makes the--
我来帮你搬  我来帮你搬
I'm pulling for you, you know? I'm pulling for you--
别提重物
No heavy lifting.
-让我来  -没事  我来吧
- I got it. - No, it's okay.
让我来
I got it.
天哪
Jesus--.
你里面放的什么呀  煤渣砖吗
What do you got in there, cinder blocks?
五十万美元现钞
Half a million in cash.
要的就是这种精神
That's the spirit.
我来吧  我来吧
I got it. I got it.
谁是来这自我完善的
Who's here for self-improvement?
来  举个手
Come on, give me a show of hands.
你们哪位希望
Who among you is here hoping
自己从此能改过自新
they can actively improve who they are?
好了
All right.
这就是你们犯的第一个错误
See, that's your first mistake.
你们来这该学的  是自我接纳
You should be here to learn self-acceptance.
亲爱的
Hey, honey, you, uh--
再来块华夫饼干吗
you want another waffle?
我还没开始收拾
I still got the iron out.
还能帮你切点香蕉
I could cut up some bananas.
你好  这里是沃尔特  斯凯勒  弗林和霍莉家
Hi, you're reached Walt, Skyler, Flynn, and Holly.
有事请留言
Please leave us a message.
大家好
Uh, hey. Hello, everybody.
早  我只是来打个招呼
Good morning. I was just checking in
再知会下我最新的联系方式
and thought I'd pass along the current contact information.
当然  有事尽管打我手机
I mean, certainly, you can always reach me on my cell.
我肯定随身带着的
I've always got that on me.
但万一要寄信的话
But in terms of a mailing address,
我现在住在长船礁[酒店名]
I'm here at The Beachcomber.
这里真不错
And you know what? It's actually very nice.
非常舒适
It's very pleasant.
虽然没有奥克伍德[酒店式公寓名]那么高端
Not as high end as the Oakwood,
但作为一家酒店...
but, you know, not as corporate--
你能帮我...
Oh, hey, would you please just--
爸  是我
Hey, Dad. It's me.
不  我不好
No, I'm not okay.
我不知道到底怎么回事
I don't know what the hell is going on.
没人他妈的跟我说怎么回事
Nobody's telling me Jack shit around here.
-弗林  别说粗话  -随便吧
- Hey, Flynn.  - What-- Whatever.
我什么都无所谓了
I-- I don't even care anymore.
你能来载我去上学吗
Can-- Can you just give me a ride to school?
我可以送你去学校
I'll take you to school.
是的  不用
Yeah. No.
我现在就准备好出发了
I-- I'm ready now.
弗林  我来送你上学
Flynn, I'm taking you to school.
好的  我来了
All right. I'm here.
待会见
See you soon.
请注意听我讲话
May I have your attention, please?
众所周知
As all of you know,
上周这座城市发生了一场可怕的悲剧
Last week our city suffered a terrible tragedy,
我们没有人会忘记
one that none of us will ever forget,
所以今天我们特意抽出时间
which is why today we're going to take a little time out of our schedule
聚集到这里谈话
to gather in the gym and talk.
我只是觉得
I just find it,
真的
You know, really
无法集中精力
really hard to concentrate
因为这些我们经历的
Because of all the horrors,
可怕的事
You know, we perceived.
让你挥之不去
It just really gets inside your brain, and
就好像在大学里
in college they have this thing where,
如果...你室友自杀了
if your roommate kills himself
如果你回到寝室
like, if you come home
发现他在壁橱或者其他什么地方吊着
and find him hanging in the closet or whatever
悲恸感顿上心头
It's basically, like, an automatic "A" for you.
我觉得这种怜悯之心
And I just think that that kind of compassion is
-是一种...  -可以了
- is something to...  - Okay.
巴里  谢谢你
Thank you, Barry.
还有谁想发言
Who wants to go next?
没有对错 只要说出你们的感受
No judgments, guys. Just feelings.
心里怎么想的
You can say anything and everything
就怎么说
That's on your mind.
有人吗
Anyone?
亲爱的  说吧
There you go, honey.
我一直在扪心自问
I just keep asking myself
亲爱的  站起来说好吗
Honey, could you please stand up?
我一直自问  为什么会发生这种事
Just keep asking myself, "Why did this happen?"
如果上帝真的存在
I mean, if there's a God and all,
他怎么能让这么多无辜的人
Why does he allow all those innocent people
无故死去
to die for no reason?
我们还是把眼光放在世俗好吗
Okay, can we just keep it secular, honey?
不管怎样  我睡眠非常不充足
Anyhow, I haven't really been sleeping much.
有人也像我一样吗
Does anyone else have that?
那个声音一直在耳边萦绕
I just keep hearing that...that sound.
爆炸声
That boom.
它一刻不休地在我脑海中回响
It just plays over and over in my head
好像永远不会停止
like it won't ever stop.
谢谢你  亲爱的
Thank you, sweetheart.
还有人想说吗
Is there anyone else?
我的邻居听到坠毁声
My neighbor, he heard the crash,
他跑到前院
and he ran out to his front yard,
他发现一个座椅
and he found, like, this seat
航空座椅
You know, like, an airline seat.
就是飞机里的那种
Like one you have on an airliner?
这个座椅稳稳当当地
Well, anyway, the seat was standing
立在他的院子里
perfectly upright in his front yard,
就在他的摩托艇旁边
right next to his Sea-Doos
是的  一艘海上摩托艇
Because, like, he has Sea-Doos
但是...
But...
就在椅子上  还有两条腿
there was still a pair of legs
卡在里面
buckled into them.
人的腿
Human legs.
你还好吧
You okay?
是的  抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
我只是有点感触
I was just moved.
让我们也来听听家长的想法
Maybe we should hear from the faculty.
他们也同样经历了这场悲剧
Certainly this tragedy didn't only affect our students.
怀特老师  你想说几句吗
Mr. White, would you like to say something?
首先欢迎你回来
And by the way, welcome back. Hmm?
你能回来实在是太好了
It's so good to have you back.
我想  我会
I guess what I would
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
我想说的是...
I guess what I would want to say is...
要往好的方面看
to look on the bright side.
首先  地面上没有出现伤亡
First of all, nobody on the ground was killed.
我是说  这样的事故是发生在
And that  I mean, an incident like this
人口众多的市中心上空
over a populated urban center
却没有伤及市民
That right there, that's  that's just gotta be
可以说是个小小的奇迹了
some minor miracle, so
而且  两架飞机都没有坐满
Plus, neither plane was full.
那架波音737仅仅
You know, the  the 737 was
大概只有
Was what? Uh,
只有三分之二的乘客
Maybe two-thirds full, I believe.
对吗
Right? Yes?
或者是四分之三
Or maybe even three-quarters full.
不管怎么说
Well, at any rate,
就遇难人数来说
What you're left with casualty-wise is
这只不过是第50大空难
Just the 50th worst air disaster.
事实上  最多排在第50了
Actually, tied for 50th.
事实上
There are, in truth,
在历史上有53次这样的空难
53 crashes throughout history
有些比这次更糟
That are just as bad or worse
特内里费
Tenerife?
你们有人
Has anybody
听说过特内里费空难吗
Anybody hear of Tenerife?
没有吗
No?
1977年  两架满乘的波音747客机
In 1977, two fully loaded 747s
在特内里费上空相撞
crashed into each other on Tenerife.
你们知道一架波音747客机有多大吗
Does anybody know how big a 747 is?
那可比波音737大多了
I mean, it's way bigger than a 737.
更别说是两架撞一起
And we're talking about two of them.
600余人丧命特内里费
Nearly 600 people died on Tenerife.
但你们对此还有印象吗
But if any of you even remember it at all?
还有人记得吗  我想没有
Any of you? I doubt it.
都知道为什么吗
You know why?
是因为
It's because...
人们都得往前看
people move on.
人们都往前看  我们也会
They just move on. And we will, too.
我们会往前看  我们会遗忘掉
We will move on, and we will get past this
这是人类的共性
because that is what human beings do.
我们能挺过去
We survive.
而且...
And, uh...
我们挺过去  并且 我们可以承受着一切
We survive, and-- and we-- we overcome.
对的 我们挺过去了 我们挺过去就
Yeah. We survive. We survive, and--
-非常感谢 -好的
Thank you. Okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
很好
Good.
你小姨玛丽最近怎么样
Hey, how's your aunt Marie doing?
我想还好吧
Fine, I guess.
进去记得替我打个招呼
You make sure you say hello to her for me, will you?
你自己干嘛不进去说 这也是你家啊
Why don't you just come inside? It's your house.
算了  我
No, I--
他走了
He's gone.
弗林回来啦
Hey, Flynn!
-你不舒服吗  -我很好  怎么了
- How's your Tricks  - I'm good. Why?
你看上去不舒服啊
Tricks. It's an expression.
还好吧
How are you?
你们为什么这么对他
Why do you gotta treat him like this?
你为什么要这样
Why you gotta be like this?
为什么你们就不能坐下来好好谈谈呢
Why can't you just talk, even?
冷静点 没事  没事的
Cool down. Okay. Okay.
终归还是个孩子啊
Out of the mouths of babes, huh?
尽量不要让这件事影响到他
You know, try not to hold it against him.
我是说
You know, I mean,
这个可怜的孩子
the poor kid, he's probably just
一定是很困惑
dying of curiosity.
我觉得困惑与执著
You know, and I guess it would be
正是他这个年龄孩子的共性
natural for him to wonder.
我想他可能只是想知道
I mean, he's probably just wondering, you know,
-到底发生了些什么  -玛丽
- what is it that could have gone so wrong.  - Marie.
-致使父母离异  -玛丽
- that my mother would leave  - Marie.
斯凯勒  如果你不跟我讲清楚
I can't help you get through this, Skyler,
沃尔特到底做了些什么
you know, if you won't tell me
-我无法帮到你的  - 你知道吗
- what it is that Walt did. - Well, you know what?
我不记得曾向你寻求过帮助吧
I don't-- I don't remember asking you, all right?
-我觉得这正是  -如果你真的想帮我
- Well, I think that's... - So if you want to be supportive,
你现在发愁的原因
the reason you're stuck.
求求你就别这么八卦了
You could be supportive without prying,
-那样会更好些  - 八卦  好吧
- that would be really great  - Prying, okay.
八卦这个词很贴切  我确实
Well, prying's a strong word, but I don't--
是在帮倒忙
...helpful.
你们脑海中
It's that...
回荡的声响
voice inside your head.
反反复复  一刻不停  让人抓狂
It's that sneaky, rat-bastard, 24/7 voice.
你们知道我说的是什么吧
You guys know what I'm talking about.
那个嘲讽你无能的声响
That voice that tells you you're not good enough.
到底什么无能
Not good enough for what? Not good enough to...
是不够格当美国总统吗
be what, President of the United States?
好吧  也许扯得太远了
Well, okay, so maybe you're not that good.
但现在你们是否有
But now are you good enough
与人分享喜怒哀乐的资格呢
to deserve your share of basic human happiness?
你们是否对自己的状况
Are you good enough to be okay
感到满意呢
with who and what you are?
我想答案是肯定的
I say yes.
但是不要管我说了什么
But it doesn't matter what I say.
那是你们脑海中的声音
It's your voice,
只有你自己能听得到
which means you're the only one that hears it,
只有你自己才能与之斗争
which means that you're the only one that can fight it.
对吧
Right?
杰西
Jesse...
从来没听你讲过话
We never hear from you.
到底怎么了
What's going on?
如果你认为我讲的全是废话
You can tell me I'm full of shit.
没事  我不介意
It's okay. I don't mind.
但是...说吧
Just... Come on.
给我们讲一讲
Let us in on it.
要说什么  你当然什么都懂
So, like, what makes you the expert?
我好像从来没这么说过
I don't think I ever said I was that.
是啊  但是坐在那里讲话的人是你吧
Yeah, but you're the one sitting here, right?
对我们说这讲那
Telling us thus and so,
要学会快乐生活  要宽恕自己云云
be happy, forgive yourself, blah, blah, blah.
但是你伤害过人吗
Have you ever really hurt anybody?
我不是指让你母亲失望之类的事
I don't just mean disappointed your mother or whatever,
但是...
but did you...
你是否真的
ever really...
伤害过别人
hurt someone?
我害死了自己的女儿
I killed my daughter.
那天是7月18日
It was July 18th...
那是我的生日
Which is my birthday.
1992年的7月18日
July 18, 1992.
我吸食了大量的可卡因
I was high on cocaine,
还喝了很多酒
and I was drunk.
可卡因不是诱因
Cocaine wasn't an issue
因为之前那晚
because I had bought myself 2 grams
我买了2克的可卡因当做自己的生日礼物
the night before as a birthday present.
那晚我还剩好多
I had plenty left.
但我喝了太多的伏特加
But I was out of vodka.
这一切都发生在弗吉尼亚的朴茨茅斯
And this is in Portsmouth, Virginia,
那地方的超市里不卖酒
Where instead of selling liquor in the supermarkets,
但ABC百货里有卖
they have these ABC stores
可是他们五点就会打烊
Which close at 5 p.m.
那时大概四点四十二分
And right then it was, like, 4:42.
我在跟我妻子争吵
So I'm arguing with my wife--
"求你了 帮我去一趟ABC吧"
"Come on, go to the ABC for me."
"今天是我的生日啊 "
"It's my birthday."
"快点"
"Come on."
"他们不会卖酒给我的"
"They're not gonna sell it to me."
她说"不去 不去"
She's saying, "No, no."
我就很生气  时间不多了
So I'm pissed, and the clock is ticking,
我就跳上车
so I jump in my truck.
她
She's--
我6岁的女儿
my 6-year-old daughter...
她在车道末端玩耍
She's playing at the end of the driveway.
于是
So...
你怎么不恨你自己呢
How do you not hate yourself?
我确实很恨我自己  恨了很长时间
I did hate myself... for a long time.
但这并没有阻止我
But it didn't stop me from...
继续酗酒  继续吸毒
drinking and getting high.
这只让事情变得更糟
It just made it that much worse.
自我憎恶  罪恶感
Self-hatred, guilt,
这些成就不了任何事情
It accomplishes nothing.
它们只能阻碍你
It just stands in the way.
阻碍你什么呢
Stands in the way of what?
真正的改变
True change.
斯凯勒
Skyler, hi.
现在方便谈谈么
Is this a good time to talk?
当然  请进
Yeah. Come in, please.
斯凯勒
Skyler.
你想开始说吗
Do you want to start?
好的
Okay.
为什么你会想出这种方式
Why are you even thinking this way?
是为了惩罚我吗
Is it to punish me?
沃尔特  我不是惩罚你
I am not punishing you, Walt.
这就是在惩罚我
This is punitive is what this is.
我们的婚姻很美满
We are happily married.
我婚后很幸福
I am happily married.
我很开心
I am happy.
我们只是
We're just--
斯凯勒  我爱你
I love you, Skyler,
我愿意为你做任何事
And I would do anything for you.
你可不可以考虑
Would you even consider--
我的意思是 天呐
I mean, Jesus!
你来我这儿
You come in here,
你把这些纸甩到我面前
And you wave these papers in my face,
这件事有着完整的两面
When there's a whole other entire side to this thing.
一面是你  一面是我
There's your side, and there's my side.
而你还没有听过我的解释
And you haven't heard my side yet.
你甚至还什么都不知道
You haven't heard any of it at all.
你是个毒品贩子
You're a drug dealer.
不是  什么  你怎么
No. What-- How--
什么
What?
是的
Yeah.
不然的话怎么解释你会赚那么多钱
How else could you possibly make that kind of money?
大麻
Marijuana.
那个叫平克曼的孩子
That Pinkman kid.
不是吗
No?
哦  我的天呐  沃尔特
Walt Oh, my God, Walt.
可卡因
Cocaine?
是甲基苯丙胺
It's methamphetamine.
甲基苯丙胺:  一种中枢兴奋药
但我  我是
But I-- I'm--
我制造
I manufacture.
但我不贩卖
I am not a dealer.
哦
Oh.
这东西本身
Per se.
它并不意味...
It doesn't mean--
斯凯勒  别这样
No, Skyler.
-斯凯勒 听我说  -不
- Listen to me, Skyler. - No.
-听着 -不
- Listen. - No.
这事有很多层面
There are a lot of angles to this, okay?
这很复杂  你明白吗  所以请你
It's complicated, all right? So please, let's--
求你了 我们坐回去
Please, let's just sit back down,
我们好好谈谈
and we'll talk it through.
沃尔特  我要跟你做笔交易
I'm gonna make you a deal, Walt.
我不会告诉汉克
I won't tell Hank,
我也不会告诉孩子们或任何人
And I won't tell your children or anybody else.
我不会走漏一丝风声
Nobody will hear it from me,
但你要答应我离婚
But only if you grant me this divorce
并且离我们的生活远远的
and stay out of our lives.
-斯凯勒别这样  -我是认真的
- No, Skyler. - I mean it.
我要赶紧离开这鬼地方  我快吐了
Now let me the hell out of here before I throw up.
你的挡风玻璃碎了
Your windshield's broken.
没错
Yep.
我的婚姻正经历一些小挫折
A little friction in the marriage right now.
非常短暂的
Strictly temporary.
我们只是
We're just--
只是需要一些空间
Just taking a little break.
你睡那儿吧
Uh, that's you over there.
听好了  关于钱的事
Listen, um, money.
索尔正替你看着呢
Saul has got it for you,
只要你感觉好点儿了
And so as so as you're feeling better--
我很好
I'm better.
你很好
You're better.
真的吗
Really?
什么  那个康复中心  有用吗
What? The rehab? It helped?
恩  我戒掉了
Yeah. I'm done using.
真是太棒了  真是
That's excellent. That's--
很好  杰西
That's very good, Jesse.
孩子  很好
Boy-- very good.
你知道...
You know, um...
不管遇到多么糟糕的情况
in spite of how bad things got,
可以把它当做
it really could be looked at
对我们的当头棒喝
like a wake-up call for both of us.
我是说  让我们...
I mean, you know, just to get our--
让我们的生活回到原轨
our lives back together again
循规蹈矩  安分守己
and on the straight and narrow.
你一直在调查飞机失事的事
You been following this airplane crash?
是啊
Yeah.
你知道是珍妮的父亲
You know it was Jane's dad
是他不经意间让飞机相撞的
who accidentally crashed them together?
是因为他身心俱惫么
Because he was so torn up?
好的  听着  我要打断一下  好吗
Okay, look, let me stop you right there, all right?
你跟这事没关系
You are not responsible for this--
一点关系都没有  好吗
not in any way, shape, or form, all right?
我...我一直在追踪这件事
Now, I-- I am very up-to-date on this thing,
也许比你知道的更多
probably far more than you are,
在这件事中有很多不确定因素
and there are-- there are many factors at play there.
是吗
Yeah?
比如
For instance,
也许飞机的防撞雷达
there's some sort of collision radar
失灵了
on the jet that may not have been working properly.
这都在公务档案上  你可以查阅一下
Now, that's public record. You can look that up.
整个系统 用的是上世纪60年代的技术
And the whole system is run on-- on 1960s technology.
不
No.
不  说真的...
No, really...
我怪罪于政府
I blame the government.
要不逃避
You either run from things,
要不就面对  怀特老师
or you face them, Mr. White.
什么意思
And what exactly does that mean?
我在康复中心学到的
I learned it in rehab.
接受最真实的自我
It's all about accepting who you really are.
我接受我是谁
I accept who I am.
那么你是谁呢
And who are you?
我是坏蛋
I'm the bad guy.
您吃得还满意吗
Is the food to your satisfaction?
很棒
Very much.
很高兴再次见到您
It's good to see you again.
我可以坐吗
May I?
有个提议我想你会感兴趣的
I have an offer that I think will be of interest to you.
实际上我到这儿来不是
I actually am not here to--
我来是因为
I'm here because
出于礼貌和对您的尊重
I owe you the courtesy and respect
我必须来当面讲明
to tell you this personally.
我要收手了
I'm done.
这个决定和您个人没有任何关系
It has nothing to do with you personally.
我觉得您相当的专业
I find you extraordinarily professional,
而且我很欣赏您做生意的方式
and I appreciate the way you do business.
我只是想
I'm just...
让我的生活有所改变
making a change in my life
并且  我...
is what it is, and I'm--
我在十字路口彷徨  举足无措
I'm at some-- something of a crossroads.
渐渐的我意识到
It has brought me to a realization.
我不是罪犯
I am not a criminal.
亦无意冒犯那些罪犯们
No offense to any people who are.
但是
But...
我不是那种人
This is not me.
尽管如此  我想让你听听我的提议
I'd like you to hear my offer, notwithstanding.
我不会改变主意的  对不起
It won't change my mind. I'm sorry.
三百万美元
$3 million.
给你三个月的时间
For three months of your time.
三个月  然后退出
Three months, then out.
三百万么
3 million?
我可以把它当做一个肯定的回答吗
May I take this as a yes?
我有钱
I have money.
我钱多的都不知道怎么花
I have more money than know how to spend.
我所缺少的是家庭
What I don't have is my family.
回答仍然是不
The answer is still no.
慢慢享用
Enjoy your meal.
谢谢
Thank you.
就是那
你感觉到了吗
德克萨斯州
这路我都走了三趟了
每次路面上都有三次剧烈的颠簸
就是你知道的
我们在德克萨斯州
可是有身份的
这次可是有一份工作在等着我呢
我老表有个车身制造车间
哟  那可是为我准备的
他们都叫我"橄榄油"  因为我刷的漆光滑溜溜的
我刷珠光颜料  能刷出所有你叫得出名字的色彩
我给米却肯州
最大的几个黑帮的车子喷漆
喔  靴子很漂亮嘛
工作的时候不方便  但是
嘿  脚尖上的是什么
小小的  银色
里面出什么事了
What the h--- is going on in there?